So far we talked about classification in terms of just predicting,
到目前为止 我们讨论分类器的时候
is this a positive sentence or a negative sentence, is email spam or not spam,
只讨论了 预测一个句子情绪是正面还是负面 一封电邮是不是垃圾邮件 这类问题
but in general, you wanna go a little bit beyond that and
但一般来说 你会想做的更多一点
ask about, what is the probability that this is email spam?
比如说 这封邮件是垃圾的概率有多大
So how confident am I on the prediction?
我对自己的预测的信心到底有多强
So if you're just looking at positive and negative,
比如说我仅仅看看结果是正还是负
I want to know how sure I am about the prediction.
那我还想知道对这个预测我到底有多肯定
So for example, if you take a sentence like, the sushi and
举例来说 如果你拿这么一个句子来分类:
everything else were awesome.
"寿司和其它所有东西都特别棒"
That's a definite plus.
这肯定是正面情绪
Definitely positive.
绝对的 "正"评价
However, the sushi was good, the service was okay.
但是 "寿司不错 服务凑合"
It's probably a plus but I'm not so sure.
这句话很可能是正面情绪 但我不能肯定
It's not as definite.
这没有前一个句子那么肯定
And so what a classifier will often do, is not just output is positive or
所以一个分类器常常不光是给出 结果是正还是负
negative, but output how confident, how sure it is.
还要给出 对这个结果 它的信心有多大
One way to do that is to talk about probabilities.
解答这个问题的方式之一 是讨论 概率
So you have to play the probability of being a positive or
所以当你输入一个句子x的时候
negative sentence, given the input sentence x.
你要输出一个这句子情绪为正或负的概率
So the output label,
因此输出的标签
what's the probability output label, given the input sentence?
就成了 给定这个句子的情况下 输出某个标签的概率是多大
So for example, for the top example there, instead of saying that's definite +,
举个例子 对最开始那个句子来说 结果就不光光是个 "+" 号
we say the probability that it's a + given x in is 0.99.
我们会说 给定那个句子x的情况下 标签为"+" 的概率是0.99
Even x is only 0.55 because I'm kind of uncertain about that.
而在第二个句子里 这个概率只有0.55 因为我不是很确定
Predicting probabilities or level of confidence is extremely important and
预测 概率/信心水平 非常非常重要
as we'll see in the classification course, it allows you to do many things.
我们在分类器那门课里 会看到它让你能做很多很多事
So for example when you know the probability, you can make decisions like,
比如说 你知道概率之后 你就可以做类似这样的决定:
what is a good decision boundary that trades off false positives and
当你知道假阳性和假阴性的不同代价 和它们之间的平衡之后
false negatives, and balance between the two.
什么决定边界才是最佳的
[MUSIC]
[背景音乐] 翻译: RyukaSuu |审阅: 19waa Coursera Global Translator Community